Shelby G. Dickerson

Plaquemine, LA • ShelbyGDickerson@outlook.com • 225-397-5713 • Linkedin.com/in/shelby-dickerson/

Objective

A "customer first" experienced Technical Support Engineer with 8+ years of experience in application maintenance and technical support, and 2+ years of experience in post-sales technical and client support. Specializing in technical support, application administration, and post-sales technical support.

Education

Grambling State UniversityB.S. Computer Information Systems

Grambling, LA December 2016

Depaul UniversityM.S. Network Engineering (32 credit hours completed)

Chicago, IL January 2020

Western Governors University

M.S. Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

Millcreek, UT Pending

Cloud Engineering Bootcamp/ROI Training

This course covered foundational knowledge and hands-on experience to provide support for cloud-based and hybrid implementations. Students learn how to manage systems that leverage cloud-native technologies and understand hybrid cloud connectivity solutions. Completing with the understanding of the following:

- Review core infrastructure fundamentals
- Understand on-premises/cloud hybrid connectivity
- Manage source code and versions using Git
- Implement containers using Docker
- Orchestrate container deployment using Kubernetes
- Automate deployment resources using Infrastructure as Code tools
- Leverage Terraform for automation

Architecting on AWS BootCamp/ExitCertified

A deep dive on AWS services, platform, and solution architect certification.

Experience

Deloitte Consulting LLC DC Support Specialist 1

New Orleans, LA (Remote) February 2022 – Present

- Ensures client success by investigating and troubleshooting technical inquiries.
- Cross-functional teamwork to deliver a quality product and experience.
- Creates and utilizes Dashboards for internal teams to ensure ticket management and improve team productivity for leading clients.
- Advocate and liaison between client and engineering teams
- Extracted weekly data to create weekly operational reports to present a general overview of weekly inquiries from clients.
- Created monthly reports to assist in monthly client success meetings for the previous month.
- On-call monitoring shifts to ensure after-hour client critical inquiries are resolved.

- Create and manage high-level support documentation to ensure existing and new associates have the proper tools and support process resources.
- Performed knowledge transfers and demoed applications to support engineers to ensure associate and client success.
- System administration and monitoring.
- User management using CIAM and Active Directory

Cerner Corporation

Malvern, PA

April 2017 – February 2022

Technical Solution Analyst

- Engaged with diverse internal teams to create projects and implement Jira solutions that would result in the team's 100% success rate in using the tool, including customized workflows and processes.
- Performed troubleshooting investigations reviewing front-end applications by gathering information, using troubleshooting tools, shadowing end users, and testing workflows internally and externally.
- Performed troubleshooting investigations via backend methods by capturing log files, querying tables, updating database fields, and updating/cycling servers.
- Successfully consolidated 5 of our biggest teams into 1 project per team, each team owning 5-15 projects, the result led to a more organized structure for the teams and increased JIRAs performance so users can get the optimal experience.
- Managed additional applications such as confluence, VersionOne, and JIRAAlign.
- Resolved over 5,000 technical queries from internal teams to resolve application-related issues.
- Managed 500+ agile projects in 3 Jira instances (production and sandbox environments)
- User/Group Management
- Created and managed technical documentation using Confluence.
- Promoted best practices to assist in successful application use.
- Used Splunk to monitor JIRA application health.

IBM

Monroe, LA

Application Development Intern

June 2016 - December 2016

- Mentee to Testing Specialist assisting in day-to-day tasks.
- Became knowledgeable in regression, acceptance, and automation testing.
- Order creation, and provisioning.
- Test case development and completion.

Skills & Certifications

Technical: Technical Support, Application Support, Networking(OSI/TCP/IP), Basic Network Troubleshooting, JIRA System Administration, Basic Linux Administration, Troubleshooting software/application issues, GitHub,Git, AWS Platform, GCP Platform, Basic Cloud Concepts, BASH/Shell, User Management

Soft Skills: Excellent Customer Service, Adaptable, Very Flexible, Excellent Communication Skills, Solution-Oriented, Team Player, Resourceful, Goal Driven, Critical Thinking

Applications: JIRA ServiceDesk, JIRA Software, Confluence, ServiceNow, Microsoft Office Suite, CIAM, OKTA, Zoom

Language: HTML, CSS, Markdown, YAML, SQL, JSQL (JIRA Specific), and Python

Certification: ITIL, Certified Scrum Master, AWS CCP